Guide to the John Nolen Jr. papers, 1906-2000 MS2193
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Planning organizations, 1925-1986; Series 2; 10.5 Linear Feet
  - Planning organizations, 1928-1986; 1935-1965; Series 2 Subseries 2; 8.5 Linear Feet
    - American Society of Civil Engineers George Washington Canal and Locks Committee correspondence and minutes, 1969-1971; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Land Use Planning Policy workshop, 1974 May; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Miscellaneous, 1943; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers National Capital Section technical division, 1963-1965; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers National Capital Section, 1948-1965; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers National Capital Section Pennsylvania Ave Development Corp. task force to review plans, 1974; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers National Capital Section convention program committee, 1959; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Planning in the Nation's Capital, 1966; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Research Council on Urban Transportation, 1966-1967; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Society Affairs, 1954-1957; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Society Affairs, 1942-1957; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Transportation Engineering meeting, 1966 April 15-16; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Urban Planning and Development Committee, 1969-1970; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Urban Planning and Development Committee, 1970-1971; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Urban Planning and Development Committee, 1971-1972; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Urban Planning and Development seminar on planning, 1973; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers Water Resources Committee, 1966-1976; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - American Society of Landscape Architects annual meetings, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - American Society of Landscape Architects corresponding member correspondence, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - American Society of Landscape Architects, 1959-1960; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - American Society of Landscape Architects Committee on Olmsted Memorial, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - American Society of Landscape Architects Potomac Chapter, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - American Society of Municipal Engineers, 1935; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - American Society of Planning Officials, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - American Society of Planners Wagner-Ellender-Taft Bill housing, 1945; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - American Society of Planning Officials planning and postwar planning - state organizations, 1945 January; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - American Society of Planning Officials, 1940; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - American Society of Planning Officials Toronto, 1965; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Belwood Farm, 1975-1982; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Belwood Farm, 1970-1981; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Board of Zoning Adjustment, 1939-1941; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Businessmen's Conference on Urban Problems Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1950 November 20-21; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City, 1969-1972; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City history, 1969-1973; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation, 1977-1980; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City Water Supply and Sewer Subcommittee, 1978-1983; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City comprehensive plan, 1981; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City planning and housing committee, 1980; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City water resources workshop, 1984 June 21; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City water, 1983, 1985; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City water, 1985-1986; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - District of Columbia Council of Engineering and Architectural Societies meeting, 1963-1967; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - District of Columbia Council of Engineering and Architectural Societies meeting, 1966-1967; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - D.C. Policy Advisory Committee minutes and socio-economic data, 1963; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - D.C. Policy Advisory Committee minutes and socio-economic data, 1963; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Georgetown Progressive Citizens Assoc., undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Interprofessional Urban Planning Committee [1/2], 1948-1949; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Interprofessional Urban Planning Committee [2/2], 1948-1949; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Lambda Alpha GW Chapter, 1966; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Lambda Alpha GW Chapter, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Lambda Alpha GW Chapter, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Lambda Alpha GW Chapter, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Lambda Alpha GW Chapter, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Lambda Alpha National Land Economics, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Lambda Alpha National Land Economics, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Lambda Alpha National Land Economics, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Lambda Alpha National Land Economics, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Lambda Alpha National Land Economics, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Lambda Alpha, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Metropolitan Washington Board of Trade Task Force on Planning Criteria, 1973; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - National Industrial Zoning Committee, undated; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee, 1932-1933; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - National Resources Committee, 1935-1936; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - National Economic and Social Planning Association, 1940; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Planning Technicians Conference, 1963; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Public Advisory Committee COG, 1982 September - October; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Public Advisory Committee COG, 1982 September - October; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Public Advisory Committee COG, 1982 April - May; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Regional Planning Federation of the Philadelphia Tri-State District, 1928-1931; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Regional Planning Federation progress report engineering, 1929; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Regional Planning Federation progress report engineering, 1929-1930; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Regional Planning Federation progress report engineering, 1930; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Regional Planning Federation progress report engineering, 1930-1931; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Torch Club of Washington D.C., 1945-1961; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Torch Club of Washington D.C. Board and Committee minutes, 1966-1971; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Torch Club of Washington D.C. member bulletins, 1961-1968; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Torch Club of Washington D.C. member bulletins, 1968-1977; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Torch Club of Washington D.C. member bulletins, 1978-1986; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Washington Area Interprofessional Council on Environmental Design, 1974; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies, 1960; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Zoning Advisory Committee, 1956-1957; Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Transportation, 1930-1986; Series 3
  Organized into 5 subseries: Correpondence, District of Columbia, Studies, reports, papers, conferences, and places outside of the District of Columbia.
  This series contains correspondence, reports, studies, and conference records related to transportation. The topics include among others highways, subways, traffic, urban mass transit, and rapid transit. The records are of work done by John Nolen during his professional life as an urban planner primarily in Washington, D.C. These records date from 1930-1986.
  Please note that series 5 contains oversize materials that do fit the subject of transportation.
  - Correspondence, 1944-1978; Series 3 Subseries 1; 0.5 Linear Feet
    - Correspondence, 1944-1976; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence transportation, 1950-1954; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - SEPACT proposal correspondence, 1962-1965; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Urban transportation correspondence, 1962-1968; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Tri-state transportation commission correspondence, 1963; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Mail ticket correspondence, 1966-1967; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence Marion Barry and Ralph Rechel, 1978; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - District of Columbia, 1930-1985; Series 3 Subseries 2; 1 Linear Feet
    - Baltimore Washington Parkway, 1976-1979; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Citizens Transit Improvements Assoc., 1961-1965; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Constitution Avenue Bridge, 1955-1957; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - D.C. Transportation, 1952-1964; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - E. Street Bridge, 1954; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Glen Echo Bus Terminal, 1985; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Metro planning and statistics, 1969-1975; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Metro Space 2 + 3 [1/2], 1971; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Metro Space 2 + 3 [2/2], 1971; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments National Capital Region Transportation Planning Board, 1968-1970; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Potomac River Bridge, 1952-1954; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Southwest Urban Renewal HUD, 1966-1968; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Traffic and parking in Washington, DC, 1939-1940; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Government of the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Safety Inspection, 1940; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Washington Area Transportation study Donald C. Hyde, 1959 October 19; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Washington DC transportation, 1930-1973; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Washington Freeway reports, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - A Washington Subway is Authorized written by Elizabeth Durham, 1982; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Wisconsin Avenue Corridor Freeway, 1959-1960; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Wisconsin Avenue Corridor Freeway, 1960; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Wisconsin Avenue Corridor Freeway, 1960; Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Studies, reports, papers, 1935-1986; Series 3 Subseries 3; 1.5 Linear Feet
    - Coalition on sensible transportation, 1986; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Drafts of D-reports [d1-d8], undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Development of electronically powered vehicles, 1967 February; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Highway and urban planning, 1962-1968; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Highway and Mass Transportation Programs, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Highway Research Board - General, 1964-1965; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Highway Research Board paper by John Nolen, Jr. Defining "Intercity" for transportation purposes, 1965 January 11; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Highway Research Board reports, 1961; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Hovercraft, undated; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Interagency transporation policy research committee - John Nolen, Jr., 1966; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Mass Transportation Commission, 1962-1963; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Mass Transportation Demonstration projects, 1966; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Mount Vernon Memorial Highway Committee, 1982; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - IPOH North-South Toll Road written by Ralph Rachel, 1979; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - P.A.L. Metro Trans Plan, 1964; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Passenger Service Improvement Corporation Loan, 1962; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Transportation People Movers, 1972; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Rand summer program in Urban Transportation, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Rapid Transit, 1959-1966; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Rapid Transit, 1968; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - The Road Builders' Profession Frederic A. Delano, 1935 January 24; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Papers by Darwin Stolzenbach, 1984; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Transit reports bibliography, 1973; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Transportation, 1957; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Transportation Nolen writings, 1964-1965; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Transportation in the Northeastern Corridor, 1962-1965; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Transportation planning, 1962-1966; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - 701 Transportation planning applications, 1963-1964; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Transportation Studies, 1963-1967; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Urban Mass Transit correspondence, 1962-1963; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Urban Mass Transportation, 1966-1967; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Urban Mass Transportation, 1967-1968; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Urban Mass Transportation planning, 1966-1968; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - UMT R and D program study D, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Urban Transportation planning, 1962-1963; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Urban Transportation Administration control record-project pending and North Leg Tree study, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Urban Transportation studies D1-D8, 1967; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Urban rapid transit, 1964 November 19; Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, 1960-1966; Series 3 Subseries 4; 0.5 Linear Feet
    - 39th annual meeting Highway Research Board pre-publication paperes, 1960; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - 39th Highway Research Board annual meeting, 1960; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - 40th Highway Research Board annual meeting papers [1/2], 1961 January 9-13; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - 40th Highway Research Board annual meeting papers [2/2], Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - 40th Highway Research Board annual meeting, 1961 January 9-13; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - 44th Highway Research Board annual meeting, 1965 January 11-15; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Model Choice a Transit planning conference Cleveland, Ohio, 1966 March 17-18; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Transportation conference Urban America, 1966; Series 3 Subseries 4 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Places outside of the District of Columbia, 1930-1984; Series 3 Subseries 5; 1 Linear Feet
    - Atlanta transit, 1962; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Ashbury Park papers, 1962; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Chicago, 1962-1963; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Cleveland, Ohio, 1945; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Cleveland, Ohio, 1965 September 29; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Detroit and Flint, 1962; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Memphis, 1963; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Montgomery County, MD, 1975-1984; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Montgomery County, MD, 1981-1984; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Northern VA regional planning commission, 1954-1962; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Philadelphia Tri-State district transportation map and scheme, 1930; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - San Diego, 1964; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Saginaw, 1965 February 23; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Miami, FL, circa 1965; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - South Central Regional conf. Tulsa Oklahoma key note address J.C. Nichols NAREB, 1936 February 12-13; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 36, Folder 3)
- Housing, 1949-1967; Series 4; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains correspondence, memorandum, newsletters, a resolution, reports, and speeches related to housing in Washington, D.C. John Nolen served as a member of the Alley Dwelling Authority. These records date from 1949-1967.
  Please note that series 5 contains oversize materials that do fit the subject of housing.
  - Alley Dwellings, 1939; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Alley Dwellings, 1940-1941; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Alley Dwelling Authority, 1940; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Alley Dwelling Authority, 1940-1941; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Alley Dwelling Housing, undated; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Federal Housing Adminstration, 1940; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Housing Citizen Council for Community Planning, 1946; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Housing, 1958; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - International Federation for Housing and Planning European tours, 1967; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Urban renewal speeches Housing and Home Finance Agency, 1950-1958; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Washington Housing Association, 1958-1960; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Washington Housing Association, 1949-1957; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 6)
- Oversize maps and planning drawings, 1906-2000; 1918-1967; Series 5
  This series contains oversize drawings and maps related to the work and college course work of John Nolen Jr. These items primarily cover the Washington DC metropolitan area although there are drawings for planning in Maine and also what is most likely Newton Massachusetts. the drawings related to Nolen's course work appear to have been drawn by him. The material ranges in date from 1906-2000 with the bulk falling between 1918-1967.
  Most of these items, based on subject, would fall within the series of transporation, housing and planning. At this time these items have not been intellectual placed in these series, but are retained in a separate series based on size.
  Arranged in no particular order.
  - Oversize folder 1, 1950-2000; Series 5 (Oversize-folder 1)
    General
    Contents of this folder include: (1) Vehicle crossing Potomac River Bridge by year and month 1950-1967; (2) Vehicles crossing Potomac River Bridge 1950-1965; (3) Vehicle crossing Potomac River Bridges by year 1950-1967; (4) 12 month moving average of vehicles crossing Potomac River Bridge 1960-1967; (5) District of Columbia Proposed Generalized Land Use map 1983-2000 and (6) Southside of PA Ave existing Fed. Bldg. N Side of PA Ave including Bldg. to remain existing Bldg. North side of PA Ave.
  - Oversize folder 2, 1976-1980; Series 5 (Oversize-folder 2)
    Contents of this folder include: (1) George Washington Memorial Parkway Great Falls Park, VA Potowmack Canal plan and profile, September 1980; (2) Topography Key Bridge to Seneca Creek GW Parkway to Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, undated; (3) National Capital Area Historic Engineering Milestones, 1776-1976; (4) Key West Ave pre-preliminary alignment Loiderman Associates, Inc, undated.
  - Oversize folder 3, 1919-1980; Series 5 (Oversize-folder 3)
    Contents of this folder include: (1) Patowmack Company Great Falls Canal, 1974; (2) Patomack Canal Work Program YYC-YACC, Summer 1980; (3) Standard No. 9 Turnout M.I.T. RR Main line, July 1919; (4) Through Plate Girder single track railroad bridge M.I.T. C.E. Dept., March 1920; (5) Force and Funicular Polygons for Cooper's C40 loading, Feb. 2, 1920; (6) Design for Wooden English Roof Truss M.I.T. C.E. Dept., March 22, 1920
    Some of the early records may be course work from Nolen's time at MIT.
  - Oversize folder 4, 1918-1920; Series 5 (Oversize-folder 4)
    Contents of this folder include: (1) Profile of contour problem / problem of contour location, July 1919; (2) Mass diagram of contour problem, undated; (3) Through plate girder single track railroad bridge, March 1920; (4) blueprit of Through plate girder single track railroad bridge, March 1920; (5) Preliminary survey for an extension of the Technology-Gardner's Point railroad, August 1918; (6) Drainage areas for a portion of Newton; (7) Design of sewerage system for a portion of Newton
    Some of these drawings appear to be from Nolen's course work at MIT
  - Oversize folder 5, 1906-1984; Series 5 (Oversize-folder 5)